New Mexico Folklife Project collection, 1984-1985
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
New Mexico Folklife Project collection 1984-1985 1984-2019
AFC 1991/032
Fleischhauer, Carl; Kalb, Laurie Beth; Pratt, Boyd C.
approximately 2685 items
2 containers: 700 manuscript materials
4 sound cassettes: analog.
9 sound tape reels: analog; 7 in.
approximately 700 film transparencies color 35 mm.
1029 film negatives black and white 35 mm.
203 film transparencies black and white, color 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in.
40 contact sheets: black and white.
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Documentation from New Mexico fieldwork conducted by Carl Fleischhauer, consultant, of the American Folklife Center, in the summers of 1984 and 1985, with folklorist Laurie Beth Kalb, for the Museum of International Folk Art (Santa Fe). In 1984, Kalb documented the art of Hispanic carvers in northern New Mexico; in 1985 she contributed to a joint project of the Museum and the New Mexico Historic Preservation Office (HPO), who had contracted with Boyd Pratt to survey historic architecture in the northeastern quadrant of New Mexico. Fleischhauer, Kalb, and Pratt conducted a short folklife survey in Clayton, Mora, and Mosquero, and other locations in New Mexico. Topics documented in field notes and sound recordings include Hispanic art, folk art and culture; Pop Shaffer's folk art environments in Mountainair; and recordings of a livestock auction in Clayton. Collection includes an extended interview with Joe Cordova of Mosquero Canyon conducted by Laurie Kalb and Boyd Pratt; an interview with Enrique Sanchez, a Cuban American living in Mosquero, interviewed by Laurie Kalb in Spanish; and an extended interview with Trinidad and Marguerito Garcia of Mosquero by Laurie Kalb and Carl Fleischhauer. Photographs were taken in La Messilla, Truchas, Velarde, Dixon, and La Cueva, in Rio Arriba County; Las Vegas, San Miguel County; Mountainair, Torrance County; and Vallecitos, N.M. by Carl Fleischhauer.
Provenance
Fleischhauer, Carl; Accessioned, 1991.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Other Repositories
The original materials and their copies are housed at The International Museum of Folk Art and the New Mexico Historic Preservation Division in Santa Fe, New Mexico.
Access and Restrictions
The New Mexico Folklife Project collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Online Content
The New Mexico Folklife Project collection is available on the Library of Congress website at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/afconline.afc1991032.
Scope and Content
Documentation from New Mexico fieldwork conducted by Carl Fleischhauer, consultant, of the American Folklife Center, in the summers of 1984 and 1985, with folklorist Laurie Beth Kalb, for the Museum of International Folk Art (Santa Fe). In 1984, Kalb documented the art of Hispanic carvers in northern New Mexico; in 1985 she contributed to a joint project of the Museum and the New Mexico Historic Preservation Office (HPO), who had contracted with Boyd Pratt to survey historic architecture in the northeastern quadrant of New Mexico. Fleischhauer, Kalb, and Pratt conducted a short folklife survey in Clayton, Mora, and Mosquero, and other locations in New Mexico. Topics documented in field notes and sound recordings include Hispanic art, folk art and culture; Pop Shaffer's folk art environments in Mountainair; and recordings of a livestock auction in Clayton. Collection includes an extended interview with Joe Cordova of Mosquero Canyon conducted by Laurie Kalb and Boyd Pratt; an interview with Enrique Sanchez, a Cuban American living in Mosquero, interviewed by Laurie Kalb in Spanish; and an extended interview with Trinidad and Marguerito Garcia of Mosquero by Laurie Kalb and Carl Fleischhauer. Photographs were taken in La Messilla, Truchas, Velarde, Dixon, and La Cueva, in Rio Arriba County; Las Vegas, San Miguel County; Mountainair, Torrance County; and Vallecitos, N.M. by Carl Fleischhauer.
Arrangement
The New Mexico Folklife Project collection is organized in 3 series:
Series 1: Manuscript materials, 1984-1985, 1987, 2019.
Series 2: Sound recordings, 1985.
Series 3: Graphic images, 1984-1985.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Fleischhauer, Carl; Kalb, Laurie Beth; Pratt, Boyd C.
Organizations
American Folklife Center; Museum of International Folk Art (N.M.); New Mexico. Historic Preservation Division
Subjects
Auctions--New Mexico.; Cuban Americans--New Mexico--Interviews.; Folk art--New Mexico.; Hispanic Americans--New Mexico--Interviews.; Livestock--New Mexico.; Vernacular architecture--New Mexico.
Places
Clayton (N.M.)--Social life and customs.; Mora (N.M.)--Social life and customs.; Mosquero (N.M.)--Social life and customs.; New Mexico--Folklore.
Form/Genre
Ethnography.; Field notes.; Interviews.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscript materials, 1984-1985, 1987, 2019
  - Inventory, 1987 (Box-folder 1/1)
    Includes the orginal and photocopy of the inventory. Also includes the updated 2019 folder list.
  - Administration - Travel Report - 1 of 2, 1984 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Administration - Travel Report - 2 of 2, 1984 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Correspondence - La Galeria de Colores - Pola and Luis Jaramillo, 1984 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Correspondence - Museum of International Folk Art - Charlene Cerny, 1984 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Correspondence - Museum of New Mexico - Lonn Taylor, 1984 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Correspondence - Office of Cultural Affairs Historic Preservation Division, State, 1984 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Correspondence - Shaffer Company - Harding Kayser, 1984 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Correspondence - Slick & Associates - Elmo Baca, 1984 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Correspondence - State of New Mexico, Office of Cultural Affairs, Historic Preservation Division - Boyd Pratt, 1984 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Correspondence - Hudgeons, Herman and Jackie, 1984 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Correspondence - Felix Lopez, 1984 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Correspondence - Maggie Olivas, 1984 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Correspondence - Eulogio Ortega, 1984 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Correspondence - Horatio Valdez, 1984 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Field Notes - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984 (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Field Notes - Laurie Kalb, 1984 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Ephemera - Supplementary Reference materials, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Booklet on Santos de New Mexico, includes an article by Elmo Baca about the architecture of Mora, New Mexico, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Two flyers advertising the opening of an exhibit organized by La Galeria de Colores, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - A map of the art galleries in Las Vegas, New Mexico, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Two business cards for Baca and Valdez, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Black-and-white contact sheets (photocopies) - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Black-and-white photo logs, Carl Fleischhauer, 1984 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Color photo logs - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984 (Box-folder 1/21)
  - Administration - Travel Report, 1985 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - Correspondence - Erma’s Famous Café - Erma Trujillo, 1985 (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Correspondence - Five State Auction - Bill Wright and Dora Russell, 1985 (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Correspondence - Holy Family Rectory, Father Douglas Raun, 1985 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Correspondence - Museum of International Folk Art - Laurie Kalb, 1985 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Correspondence - The Store - Andy Trujillo, 1985 (Box-folder 1/27)
  - Correspondence - Mr. and Mrs. Joseph Cordova, 1985 (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Correspondence - Mr. and Mrs. Margarito Garcia, 1985 (Box-folder 1/29)
  - Correspondence - Sonia Raftery, 1985 (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Correspondence - Mr. and Mrs Lloyd Tower, 1985 (Box-folder 1/31)
  - Field Notes - Laurie Kalb, 1985 (Box-folder 2/32)
    Contents removed.
  - Field Notes - Laurie Kalb, 1985 (Box-folder 2/33)
    Includes correspondence with Carl Fleischhauer along with notes from Lauie Kalb and field notes.
  - Field Notes - sound recording tape boxes documentation (photocopy) - Laurie Kalb, 1985 (Box-folder 2/34)
  - Field Notes - Carl Fleischhauer, 1985 (Box-folder 2/35)
    Also includes printed and handwritten sketches of the areas visited.
  - Field Notes supplement - Carl Fleischhauer (corrected and revised), 2019 (Box-folder 2/35-1)
  - Report - Cultural Conservation Project - New Mexico - Laurie Kalb, 1985 (Box-folder 2/36)
  - Report draft - Cultural Conservation Project - New Mexico - Boyd Pratt, 1985 (Box-folder 2/37)
  - Black-and-white negatives documentation, 1985 (Box-folder 2/38)
    Note indicating the relocation of the negatives.
  - Black-and-white negatives documentation, 1985 (Box-folder 2/39)
  - Black-and-white photo logs - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2/40)
  - Color photo logs - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2/41)
  - Color slides - phonyfiche Fleischhauer, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2/42)
  - Color slides - phonyfiche, 1984-1985 (1/2) (Box-folder 2/43)
  - Reference color slides - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2/44)
  - Black-and-white contact sheets - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984-1985 (1/3) (Box-folder 2/45)
  - Black-and-white contact sheets - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984-1985 (2/3) (Box-folder 2/46)
  - Black-and-white contact sheets - Carl Fleischhauer, 1984-1985 (3/3) (Box-folder 2/47)
- Series 2: Sound recordings, 1985
  - Auctioneer chant at the weekly auction, Five State Livestock Auction Co. Inc., Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, NM85-LK-R1; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR01)
  - Conversations at the community bench on the main street, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, NM85-LK-R2; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR02)
  - Interview with Joe Cordova and Alisandra Cordova about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985 (part 1 of 3), NM85-LK-R3; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR03)
  - Interview with Joe Cordova and Alisandra Cordova about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985 (part 2 of 3), NM85-LK-R4; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR04)
  - Interview with Joe Cordova and Alisandra Cordova about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985 (part 3 of 3), NM85-LK-R5; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR05)
  - Interview with Enrique Sanchez, ranch worker, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, NM85-LK-R6; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR06)
  - Interview with Margarito Garcia and Trinidad Garcia about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985 (part 1 of 3), NM85-LK-R7; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR07)
  - Interview with Margarito Garcia and Trinidad Garcia about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985 (part 2 of 3), NM85-LK-R8; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR08)
  - Interview with Margarito Garcio and Trinidad Garcia about life in Mosquero Canyon, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985 (part 3 of 3), NM85-LK-R9; 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in. (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR09)
  - Union County Fair, interviews with fair participants Ruth Shields, Max Geary, and Joanne Butt, Clayton, New Mexico, August 15, 1985, NM85-LK-A1; 1 60-minute audiocassette (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR10)
  - Interview with Erma Trujillo, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 22, 1985, NM85-LK-A2; 1 60-minute audiocassette (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR11)
  - Interview with Charles "Chuck" Payne and Linda Leak at the Five State Livestock Auction Co. Inc., Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, NM85-LK-A3; 1 60-minute audiocassette (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR12)
  - Interview with Lloyd Tower and Irene Tower about the Dawson houses, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, NM85-LK-A4; 1 60-minute audiocassette (Item-id AFC 1991/032: SR13)
- Series 3: Graphic materials, 1984-1985
  - Eulogio Ortega, artist, Velarde, New Mexico; Horacio Valdez's house and studio, Dixon, New Mexico, June 23, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-01)
  - Felix Lopez, artist, at home and in studio, La Mesilla, New Mexico, June 22, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-02)
  - Historical buildings and neighborhood, Mora, New Mexico; Fence at Pop Shaffer hotel, Mountainair, New Mexico, June 25, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-03)
  - Horacio Valdez, artist, Dixon, New Mexico, June 23, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-04)
  - Chair in dining room, Pop Shaffer Hotel, Mountainair, New Mexico, June 26, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-05)
  - La Galeria de Colores, Luis and Pola Jaramillo, Las Vegas, New Mexico, June 24, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-06)
  - Pop Shaffer Hotel and Rancho Bonito, Harding Kayser and Joe Brazil, Mountainair, New Mexico, June 25-26, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-07)
  - San Francisco de Asis Mission Church, Rancho de Taos, New Mexico; Our Lady of the Rosary Mission Church and other scenes, Truchas, New Mexico; Eulogio Ortega, artist, Velarde, New Mexico, June 23, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-08)
  - Felix Lopez, artist, at home and in studio, La Mesilla, New Mexico, June 22, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-09)
  - Galeria de Colores, Las Vegas, New Mexico; Mill and San Rafael Church, La Cueva, Mora County, New Mexico, June 24-25, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-10)
  - Pop Shaffer Hotel and Rancho Bonito, Jackie Hudgeons and Herman Hudgeons, Mountainair, New Mexico, June 25, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-11)
  - Felix Lopez's home and studio, La Mesilla, New Mexico; Interior of chapel build by Eulogio Ortega and painted by Zoraida Ortega, Velarde, New Mexico, June 22-23, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-12)
  - Horacio Valdez's home and studio, Dixon, New Mexico; Pop Shaffer Hotel, Mountainair, New Mexico, June 23-26, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-13)
  - Horacio Valdez's home and studio, Dixon, New Mexico; Pop Shaffer Hotel, Harding Kayser and Joe Brazil, Mountainair, New Mexico, June 23-24, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-14)
  - Chapel built by Eulogio Ortega and painted by Zoraida Ortega, and their workshop, Velarde, New Mexico, June 23, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 226152-15)
  - Building described as Penitente morada, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico; Pacheco ranch buildings and water reservoir, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico, August 23, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-01)
  - Scenes in Mosquero, New Mexico; Alisandra Cordova and Joe N. Cordova, grandchildren, and interview, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-02)
  - Pat's City Bar, Trujillo family portrait, Erma's Coffee Shop, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-03)
  - Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-04)
  - Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico; Houses from Dawson coal mine company town, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-05)
  - Roadside chapel and other scenes on the road, San Miguel County, New Mexico; Scenes in Clayton, New Mexico, August 27-28, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-06)
  - Pacheco ranch, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico; Cordova ranch, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico; Erma Trujillo interview, Mosquero, New Mexico;, August 31, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-07)
  - Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-08)
  - Garcia family home, Mosquero, New Mexico; Garcia ranch buildings and windmill, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico, August 30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-09)
  - Erma's Coffee Shop, Pat's City Bar, historic photograph, the bench at Trujillo's store, Andy Trujillo's sculpture, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-10)
  - St. Joseph's Church, Trujillo home, the bench at Trujillo's store, interview with Margarito Garcia and Trinidad Garcia, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-11)
  - Garcia ranch buildings and Pacheco ranch house, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico; Scenes on the road between Mosquero Canyon and Mosquero, New Mexico; St. Joseph's Church, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-12)
  - Erma Trujillo interview, Mosquero, New Mexico; Photos from Margarito Garcia's and Trinidad Garcia's family album, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 31, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-13)
  - Lloyd Tower and Irene Tower, Clayton, New Mexico; Scenes in and near Hayden, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-14)
  - Alisandra Cordova and Joe Cordova, grandchildren, and interview, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-15)
  - Alisandra Cordova and Joe Cordova, grandchildren, rodeo practice, and interview, Mosquero, New Mexico; St. Joseph's church and other scenes in Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29-30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-16)
  - Scenes in Clayton, New Mexico; Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-17)
  - Pacheco ranch house, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico; Building described as Penitente morada, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico, August 31, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-18)
  - St. Joseph's Church, Mosquero, New Mexico; Bettina Raphael's yard, Santa Fe, New Mexico, August 31, 1985 - September 1, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-19)
  - Scenes in Clayton, New Mexico; Historic photograph of Mosquero, New Mexico, August 28-29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-20)
  - Town-center businesses and townscape from the south, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29-30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-21)
  - Historic photograph of Mosquero, New Mexico; Town-center businesses, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-22)
  - Albert Trujillo with self portrait and family members, Pat's City Bar and Erma's Coffee Shop, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-23)
  - St. Joseph's church, Mosquero, New Mexico; Home of Margarito Garcia and Trinidad Garcia, Mosquero, New Mexico; Garcia ranch house, Mosquero Canyon, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 2 1/4 x 2 1/4 in. black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 233070-24)
  - Scenes in and near Mancos, Colorado, 1984, unnamed; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 234633-01)
  - Scenes in Vallecitos, Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, September 16-17, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm black-and-white film negatives (Item-id AFC 1991/032: 234633-02)
  - Scenes in Vallecitos, Rio Arriba County, New Mexico, September 16-17, 1984, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-C018)
  - Roadside chapel and other scenes on the road, San Miguel County, New Mexico; Scenes in Clayton, New Mexico, August 27-28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-01)
  - Scenes in Clayton, New Mexico; Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-02)
  - Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-03)
  - Five State Livestock Auction, Clayton, New Mexico; Houses from Dawson coal mine company town, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-04)
  - Houses from Dawson coal mine company town, Lloyd Tower and Irene Tower, Clayton, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-05)
  - Scenes in and around Hayden, New Mexico, August 28, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-06)
  - Laurie Kalb interviewing Enrique Sanchez, and Albert Trujillo with self portrait and family members, Pat's City Bar and Erma's Coffee Shop, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-07)
  - Pat's City Bar, historic photograph, the bench at Trujillo's store, Andy Trujillo's sculpture, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-08)
  - Alisandra Cordova and Joe Cordova, grandchildren, and interview, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-09)
  - Alisandra Cordova and Joe Cordova, quilts, and interview, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-10)
  - Alisandra Cordova and Joe Cordova, grandchildren, rodeo practice, and interview, Mosquero, New Mexico; Scenes in Mosquero, New Mexico, August 29, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-11)
  - St. Joseph's Roman Catholic Church, building and grounds, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-12)
  - St. Joseph's Roman Catholic Church, building and grounds, scenes of the town, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-13)
  - The bench at Trujillo's store, scenes in town, interview with Margarito and Trinidad Garcia, Mosquero, New Mexico, August 30, 1985, Carl Fleischhauer; 35 mm color slide (Item-id AFC 1991/032: CF-14)